Alright, our crawler is run
and Phase C, we shows one table change here we go back
to databases here, and then go to our mission dh,
H-F-C-D-L-C.
We should see our curated, uh, table right here
and go to actions here and click on view data.
It'll take us to Athena,
which will fire the query automatically for us.
And that query is in fact now getting run here.
And it is run here, by the way.
And our job is now to do some spot checks.
Whether this data you see here in the curated table is
as per the expectation mentioned in the mapping sheet,
or no, here we have the logic info, right?
So we gotta be looking at the different, uh,
transformation logic, which each and every file, each
and every column here, right?
These columns and validating whether
these transformations have been properly as, uh,
applied or not.
Okay? For example, look at these ones here.
You have shared request flags.
You have case and y equal to this.
You should be seeing true or false.
If you go back to our query editor
and take a look at those fields here, in fact, these, uh,
you should see true and false.
False, false, false. So it does mean that yes,
transformation is finished.
And so we could,
we typically do a spot check of the different records.
And here as well, day of the week,
let's take a look at them.
And, um, it shows Sunday, Sunday, Sunday, right?
So we gotta be doing our unit testing as data engineers.
Our job as a part of development is also to unit test.
Uh, all the logic that we have applied,
whether it has successfully implemented by in our code
and the output is as per the expectation
or not, is what we need to be checking.
And we then fill a unit testing template, which is sort
of approved for us to, uh, conclude
that unit testing has been successful.
And if we, if we find any issues, uh, by
during unit testing, we go back and look at the code
and fix the code and, you know, uh, run the job again
and then do unit testing till we are satisfied.
That data is per the mapping sheet.
Only when our unit testing is finished,
that is when we actually hand over the data
to the data analysts.
Okay? So now let's say assume that data, uh,
the unit testing is all good.
We have validated by firing a lot of different queries here,
uh, looking at different fields in this, uh, data set.
And, uh, it is absolutely per the transformation logic.
Then we inform the data analysts, Hey,
we have lowered the two years of data in the curated layer.
Now you go and you can take a look at the data
and do your analysis.